<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>fedtechrants -></title>
 <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2014-12-31T15:36:46+00:00</updated>
 <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Federico Maffei</name>
   <email>federico.maffei@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>A Beginner's guide to REST services</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/12/29/REST-whatisit/"/>
   <updated>2014-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/12/29/REST-whatisit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction-to-rest&quot;&gt;Introduction to REST&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REST stands for Representational State Transfer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is an architectural style used to build Web Services that are lightweight, maintainable, and scalable. A service that uses it is called a &lt;strong&gt;RESTful service&lt;/strong&gt;. REST is not strictly dependent on any protocol, but very often uses HTTP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of a web service can be summed up as follows: it exposes &lt;strong&gt;resources&lt;/strong&gt; to its &lt;strong&gt;clients&lt;/strong&gt; so that they can access them (example of typical resources: pictures, video files, web pages, business data).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common features of a service that is built in a REST style are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Representations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;URIs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uniform Interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stateless&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Links between resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;representations---what-are-they?&quot;&gt;Representations - what are they?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REST style does not put a constraint into the way resources are represented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good examples of data formats in which a resource could be returned from a service are &lt;strong&gt;JSON&lt;/strong&gt; (JavaScript Object Notation, which nowadays is the coolest one) and &lt;strong&gt;XML&lt;/strong&gt; (Extensible Markup Language, used for more complex data structures). Say for instance a REST service has to expose the data related to a song, with its attributes. A way of doing it in JSON could be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-json&quot; data-lang=&quot;json&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;ID&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;(You gotta) Fight for your right (To party)&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;artist&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Beastie Boys&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;album&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Licensed To Ill&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;year&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1986&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;genre&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hip-Hop&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy, huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, a service can represent a resource in a number of ways at the same time, leaving the client to choose which one is better suited for its needs. The important thing is that there is agreement on what format to send/expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The format that the client needs will be part of the &lt;strong&gt;request&lt;/strong&gt; sent by the client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resource will be eventually sent by the service as part of what we call a &lt;strong&gt;response&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has to be kept in mind that a resource should be completely described by the representation, since this is the only information the client will have. It has to be exaustive, but without exposing classified or useless information about the entity at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;messages-a.k.a.-client-and-service-chatting&quot;&gt;Messages A.K.A. client and service chatting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: So, how do exactly client and service exchange requests and responses?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: They send messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, to be more specific, the client will send an &lt;strong&gt;HTTP request&lt;/strong&gt; to the service, specifying the following details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;method&lt;/strong&gt; that is called on the resource. It can correspond to a &lt;em&gt;GET&lt;/em&gt;, a &lt;em&gt;POST&lt;/em&gt;, a &lt;em&gt;PUT&lt;/em&gt;, a &lt;em&gt;DELETE&lt;/em&gt;, an &lt;em&gt;OPTIONS&lt;/em&gt; or a &lt;em&gt;HEAD&lt;/em&gt; operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;URI&lt;/strong&gt; of the request. It identifies what is the resource on which the client wants to use the method on. More on that later. For now let&amp;#39;s say it is the only way the client know how to call the needed resource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;HTTP version&lt;/strong&gt;, which is usually &lt;em&gt;HTTP/1.1&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;request headers&lt;/strong&gt;, which are the additional information passed, with the request, to the service. These fields are basically request modifiers, similar to the parameters sent to a programming language method, and they depend on the type of request sent. More on that later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;request body&lt;/strong&gt;: is the actual content of a message. In a RESTful service, it’s where the representation of resources sit. A body will not be present in a GET request, for instance, since it is a request to retrieve a resource rather than to create one, whereas a POST request will most likely have one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The request will then generate an &lt;strong&gt;HTTP response&lt;/strong&gt; to the client, that will contain the following elements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;HTTP version&lt;/strong&gt;, same as above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;response code&lt;/strong&gt;: which is a three-digit status code sent back to the client. Can be of the &lt;strong&gt;1xx&lt;/strong&gt; format (informational), &lt;strong&gt;2xx&lt;/strong&gt; (success), &lt;strong&gt;3xx&lt;/strong&gt; (redirect), &lt;strong&gt;4xx&lt;/strong&gt; (client error), &lt;strong&gt;5xx&lt;/strong&gt; (server error).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;response header&lt;/strong&gt;, which contains metadata and settings related to the message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;response body&lt;/strong&gt;: contains the representation (if the request was successful).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;uris,-home-of-the-resources&quot;&gt;URIs, home of the resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A requirement of REST is that each resource has to correspond to an URI address, which unsurprisingly stands for Uniform Resource Identifier. Having URIs associated to resources is key, because they are the addresses on which the client is allowed to perform the operations on the resources. It is important to stress that according to REST an URI should describe a resource, but never the operation performed on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The addresses are usually constructed hierarchically, to allow readability. A typical resource URL could be written as:
&lt;strong&gt;http://serviceName/resourceName/resourceID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic guidelines to build well-structured URIs are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resources should be named with plural nouns, no verbs, using conventions throughout the whole service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Query URIs (http://serviceName/resourceName?id=resourceID) should be used only when really necessary. They are not deprecated by REST style, but they are less readable than the normal URIs, and are ignored by search engines. On the upside, they allow the client to send parameters to the service, to refine the request for a specific subset of resources, or resources in a specific format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;uniform-interface,-various-operations&quot;&gt;Uniform interface, various operations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so now that a client knows where a resource is reachable, how is it going to handle the resource? What are the operations that it can perform?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTTP provides a set of methods that allow the client to perform standard operations on the service:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Method&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Operation performed&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Quality&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Read a resource&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Safe&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;POST&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Insert a new resource, or update an existing one&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PUT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Insert a new resource, or update an existing one&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Idempotent (see below)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DELETE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Delete a resource&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Idempotent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPTIONS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;List allowed operations on a resource&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Safe&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HEAD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Return only the response header, no body&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Safe&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key difference between &lt;em&gt;POST&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PUT&lt;/em&gt; is that no matter how many times a &lt;em&gt;PUT&lt;/em&gt; operation is performed, the result will be the same (this is what &lt;em&gt;idempotent&lt;/em&gt; means), whereas with a &lt;em&gt;POST&lt;/em&gt; operation a resource will be added or updated multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another difference is that a client that sends a &lt;em&gt;PUT&lt;/em&gt; request always need to know the exact URI to operate on, I.E. assigning a name or an ID to a resource. If the client is not able to do so, it has no choice but to use a POST request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if the resource already exists, &lt;em&gt;POST&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PUT&lt;/em&gt; will update it in an identical fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;statelessness-of-the-client-side&quot;&gt;Statelessness of the client side&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A RESTful service does not maintain the application state client-side. This only allow the client to perform requests that are resource specific, and does not allow the client to perform operations that assume prior knowledge of past requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;links-between-resources&quot;&gt;Links between resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in the case of a resource that contains a list of resources, REST suggests to include links to the single resources on the representation, to keep it compact and avoid redundant data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;caching-to-optimize-time-and-efficiency&quot;&gt;Caching to optimize time and efficiency&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allows to store responses and return them if the same request is performed again. It has to be handled carefully to avoid returning stale results. The headers that allow us to perform controls over caching are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Header&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Application&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Finding out when this representation was generated&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last Modified&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Date and time when the server modified the representation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cache-Control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HTTP 1.1 header used to control caching, can contain directives&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expires&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Expiration date (supports HTTP 1.0)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Age&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Duration since the resource was fetched from server&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cache-Control values can be tweaked to control if a cached result is still valid or stale. For example, the &lt;em&gt;max-age&lt;/em&gt; value indicates for how many seconds from the moment expressed by the Date header a cached result will be valid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REST is a language-agnostic style that allows to build scalable, reusable and relatively lightweight web services. Thinking about it, seems that REST is nothing more than a description of the characteristics that made the World Wide Web so popular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That of course is encouraging developer from all over the world to comply to these very basic ideas, owned by no one but at the same time used by everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that lead me to this realization: for this first 6 months or so, I have been developing REST services on Rails, Node and so on, without knowing it ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Job.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/11/17/newjob/"/>
   <updated>2014-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/11/17/newjob</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After three months I am a bit scared to reopen the blog. Like you&amp;#39;d be scared of eating something that has been left in a fridge for the same amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, in this tech thing three months without any update make something old and stale. And maybe that&amp;#39;s why I love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But anyway...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a job, in an amazing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opentable.co.uk&quot;&gt;company&lt;/a&gt; that seemed to believe I wasn&amp;#39;t cheating when I said I actually started to write computer code less than 6 months ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/ot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;OPENTABLE&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think it is time to blow some dust off the blog, and use it to write less personal and more technical posts, that I&amp;#39;m sure at the beginning will be very rudimentary, but hopefully at some point progress and start being interesting for the reader.
A key concept that is oldie but goldie: teaching and writing about topics is the way to learn and master them. Or at least make it seem you do ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when that time will come, I&amp;#39;ll aim higher and try to be more opinionated, updated about technologies and understand the why, not only the how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Graduation!</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/08/13/graduation/"/>
   <updated>2014-08-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/08/13/graduation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s often wise to sit down and let some time pass after something important happens in your life, before trying to get some sense out of it, especially if you want to write some stuff about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a Makers Academy graduate, in the end. This has been a wild ride. Something I will not forget, ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduation day has been very similar to the whole experience: a rollercoaster of emotions, good and bad ones, as often happens in 25, City Road. My cohort mates&amp;#39; projects were all incredible and clearly showed eveyone how people get real skills here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s start talking a bit about the good things and peoples: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The project, which has been an invaluable test for both coding and working in a team. I would be really glad if you, kind reader, would like to check the final product out at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://workmap.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;http://workmap.herokuapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The classmates and teammates, people that will go very far in life, all of them, I have no doubt about that. I hope not to lose contact with anyone, and I will put effort in making sure that doesn&amp;#39;t happen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teachers and coaches, which I will never thank enough for their dedication, patience and commitment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone working for Makers. The team is extraordinary, and made of lovely people who also make great professionals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me. I usually refrain from patting myself on the back, but all in all I feel proud of myself. It&amp;#39;s not easy to endure such an intensive class, and I did it, even with a broken arm. Well done!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only bad things that I can think of is that I didn&amp;#39;t like the presentation speech I gave to explain part of the final project to the people attending the graduation Open Day. I got too emotional, did not manage to talk the way I wanted about the amazing features my team built. I want to improve on that, and together with finding a good job, this is now my most important task to do. Public speaking is important, and I know I can do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Makers never stops teaching you lessons, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, off to the seaside. I&amp;#39;ll use the blog to talk about coding anyway in the future, so this won&amp;#39;t be the last time you hear from me. Thanks for reading, I be out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/sea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SEA&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 61 - Project Day 5.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/28/day-61/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/28/day-61</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Weekend? 8 hours of sleep in three days. Today? Really not great. Still at Makers, trying to get something good out of this day. Here&amp;#39;s how I look like. Self explanatory, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/monday.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MONDAY&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2q9_ZEtuTR8&quot;&gt;Maybe tomorrow.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 59 - Project Day 4.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/24/day-59/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/24/day-59</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;array!&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@jobs&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;advert_title&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;advert_title&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;address&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;address&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;company&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;company&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;category&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;category&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;latitude&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;latitude&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;longitude&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;longitude&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;detail&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;detail&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;email&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;email&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;phone&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;phone&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wage&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wage&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;hours&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;full_time?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Full time&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Part time&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hectic day today, started with the usual Standup Meeting with Jordan. Here&amp;#39;s all the team, glorious screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/meeting.png&quot; alt=&quot;MEETING&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we went on with the development of our creature, WorkMap. The deadline to deliver a shippable product, as per Agile specifications, is this Sunday. Then we&amp;#39;ll begin the second and last Sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means a rush of four days, in which we have to tackle 3 main aims:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be sure that all the jobs inserted by the employer are in the map, and allow the user to filter them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make a good looking landing page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be sure that the employer can edit the jobs he inserted, and pays for the newly added advert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I have been working with Robin, trying to tackle the jobs filtering on the map. It turned out that all the code that I wrote to make checkboxes filter results was pretty useless, since now we settled for a filtering form, allow us to render the results of the search in &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JSON&quot;&gt;JSON format&lt;/a&gt;. This way we can pass all the information related to jobs from the Rails back end to the Javascript front end, and viceversa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, two full days of work to Sunday. Better get some rest, yo.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 58 - Project Day 3.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/23/day-58/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/23/day-58</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Job&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;ActiveRecord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Base&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;validates&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:advert_title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;presence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;maximum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;40&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;minimum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;validates&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:company&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;presence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;maximum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;40&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;minimum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;validates&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:address&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;presence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;validates&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:wage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;numericality&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;only_integer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;validates&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;format&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/\A[_a-z0-9-]+(\.[_a-z0-9-]+)*@[a-z0-9-]+(\.[a-z0-9-]+)*(\.[a-z]{2,4})\z/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;belongs_to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:employer&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;geocoded_by&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:address&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;after_validation&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:geocode&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productive day, today, even if tiring as usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I notice that, at night, even if only a few hours passed since I coded, I can hardly remember exactly what happened to me during the day. Not to mention if I start thinking about the days before! It&amp;#39;s all a confused blur of Ruby lines, team talking and a coffee every once in a while. I guess that everything will make sense when the course will be finished and the project will be out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The WorkMap application is alive and kicking, if you were curious about it. If you weren&amp;#39;t, no problem, it&amp;#39;s going to be so famous you&amp;#39;ll talk about it to your friends not too far along the line, chief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lion&amp;#39;s share of work is still Google Maps related, since we are trying to filter the results on the map and show only the relevant results to the job-searching-user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, OK, I&amp;#39;ll post a glimpse of the main page. Taken at 9pm, while still trying to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/preview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PREVIEW&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More things to come in the next days. I&amp;#39;ll sleep when I&amp;#39;m dead.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 57 - Project Day 2.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/22/day-57/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/22/day-57</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;map&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;google&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;maps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;getElementById&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;map-canvas&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;mapOptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tough day, this second project day, definitely tougher than yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team is still going strong, but I can feel we are slowly drifting away from our comfort zone (Rails and a bit of front end), to begin exploring the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of the application we want to delivery next Sunday is based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/maps/&quot;&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt;, and the challenges related are many. We want to be able to store job into markers, show and hide them according to the user input, and allow a pop-up with info to appear when a marker is clicked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today has been fairly productive, but I don&amp;#39;t want to talk too much too soon. Everyone is working hard, and it feels good to be finally functional, typing with both my hands and not feeling pain. A sensation I learned not to take for granted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off to sleep, yo.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 56 - Project Day 1.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/21/day-56/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/21/day-56</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Project WorkMap - day one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have to say it was a pretty good day, even better than I expected. It felt really nice to create the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/federicomaffei/WorkMap&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt; named WorkMap, and starting working on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a really brief standup meeting with Jordan via chat, then proceeded to pair (I worked with Robin, James W with Sasha, and James K acted as a plus one in their team). The day was fairly productive, and by the end of the afternoon we had tackled a good half of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrum_%28software_development%29#Product_backlog&quot;&gt;Product Backlogs&lt;/a&gt; we wanted to work on. Everyone looked happy with the work done, and I am really glad of being part of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now an employer can sign up, sign in, insert a new job, and see it on a nice Google Map. Not bad for now, huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then in the evening I went with Valentina, Will, Kate and Margherita to a Burger competition called BurgerMonday. It was one of the two semifinals, and the food was amazing. The two contenders were Hawksmoor and Disco Bistro, both well renowned London resturants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/burgers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BURGERS&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tough decision for me, but I had to vote for Hawksmoor, since the girl at the counter gave me a huge double burger to bias me. Mission accomplished!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On to day two.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Weekend - Kick Off!</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/20/weekend/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/20/weekend</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sunday, team meeting and time for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrum_%28software_development%29&quot;&gt;Scrum Kick-off.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Scrum development framework, which we chose to use to build the final project, relies on three key roles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Product Owner: he Product Owner is typically the individual closest to the &amp;quot;business side&amp;quot; of the project. The Product Owner is typically charged by the organization to &amp;quot;get this product out&amp;quot;. In this case, Jordan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Development Team: cross-functional group of people who, among them, have all the necessary skills to deliver each increment of the product. In this case, us!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Scrum Master: a facilitator, the interface between the Team and the Owner, that help the Team focusing on the work to be done. In this case, Jordan again!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had two meetings: a &lt;a href=&quot;http://guide.agilealliance.org/guide/backlog-grooming.html&quot;&gt;Backlog Grooming Session&lt;/a&gt;, in which we analyzed the user stories we had in mind for the WorkMap product, and translated them into a Product Backlog, which is the list of the stories to be developed, ordered by priority. It is very important to keep the product simple and try to be delivering a working copy at the end of the first spring (first week, in our case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, having decided which stories are most important for this first cycle of production (that we arleady know is called Spring), we had a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mountaingoatsoftware.com/agile/scrum/sprint-planning-meeting/&quot;&gt;Spring Planning Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, in which we tried to estimate how long it could take to develop and deliver each user story. To do that we used casino fiches. If we thought that the time needed to develop that feature was short we had to put a white fiche on the table, if medium a green one, if large a red one, if unbearably large a black one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/fiches.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FICHES&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have a good plan for next week. User stories that are to be analyzed, understood and put into code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exciting. I can&amp;#39;t wait until it is Monday, and that should tell you how good it feels to be building something of our own.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 54.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/17/day-54/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/17/day-54</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not much blogging this week, I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But time has come, and I can tell you a bit more about the final project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have chosen to participate in a project that is a bit experimental. In fact I&amp;#39;ll be developing an idea pitched by our marketing man Jordan, that offered to guide a group of us in two weeks of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agile_software_development&quot;&gt;Agile Development&lt;/a&gt; of a job-searching-and-posting platform called WorkMap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be working with James W, Sasha, Robin, and James K.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile Development is based on a really simple and incisive manifesto, that reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are uncovering better ways of developing software by doing it and helping others do it. Through this work we have come to value:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Individuals and interactions over Processes and tools&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working software over Comprehensive documentation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Customer collaboration over Contract negotiation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Responding to change over Following a plan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, while there is value in the items on the right, we value the items on the left more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two weeks will be divided in two so-called Sprints, starting this Sunday, when we&amp;#39;ll focus on building User Stories related to this project, and find out what we&amp;#39;ll be developing first. Jordan will act as Product Owner, and we will discuss with him the requirements of the project, creating the Product Backlog. That first phase will be called Product Backlog Grooming session. Then we will estimate the time needed for completing each task related to the PBI, in a second part of the meeting called Sprint Planning Session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then on Monday we&amp;#39;ll start coding! And I am really happy to say that while I&amp;#39;m doing it, I&amp;#39;m realizing I like it, and working on a weekend is not annoying at all. An this is the main answer I was expecting to have from these three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good things to come. Hopefully I&amp;#39;ll be able to blog all over the completion of the finished product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and tonight London sky looks pretty great. May you all have the weekend you wish for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/sky.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SKY&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 51.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/14/day-51/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/14/day-51</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;times&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Final project!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All right, week number ten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that there are other three weeks left to go, and a week left to the final projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pizzagram.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;Pizzagram&lt;/a&gt; application is beginning to resemble a real world one, plus today we covered a big meaty topic: using &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/&quot;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt; to sell printed pictures and get revenue from the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/stripe.png&quot; alt=&quot;STRIPE&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The integration with Rails is seamless, since Stripe provides a detailed and well written &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/checkout/guides/rails&quot;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt;. All you have to do is set up a model and controller for the charges, add the private key for your account to the secrets file, and start getting that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PBwAxmrE194&quot;&gt;cream&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week my blogging is going to be on-and-off, since I want to be ready for the project, for which I want to be blogging everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$ bill, yo.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 49.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/10/day-49/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/10/day-49</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;/posts/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;postId&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;.json&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;map&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;GMaps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;#map&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;lat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;lng&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;

            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;GMaps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;geocode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;address&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;address&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;callback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;results&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;status&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;status&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;OK&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;latlng&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;results&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;geometry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;location&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;setCenter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;latlng&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;lat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;latlng&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;lng&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;());&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;addMarker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;
                            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;lat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;latlng&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;lat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
                            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;lng&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;latlng&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;lng&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;alert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Could not find address&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My pizzagram app is getting cooler and cooler.&lt;br&gt;
Now it integrates &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/maps/&quot;&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt; to the service, so now a user can enter an address along with the post, which triggers the creation of a link with a map that points to the exact address. Nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, I managed to push it to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heroku.com/about&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;, which is the cloud service we will use to make our applications available to the public, for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to have a look at my humble work, click &lt;a href=&quot;http://pizzagram.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/pizza.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HOMER&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Away, to eat pizza of course.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 48.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/09/day-48/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/09/day-48</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;jumbotron&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;container&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Welcome to Pizzagram.&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;This is a website that includes amazing pictures of pizzas of all flavours. Buonissimo.&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;%= link_to &amp;#39;Sign Up &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;#39;, new_user_registration_path, class:&amp;quot;btn btn-primary btn-lg&amp;quot;%&amp;gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram app coding proceeding. I got quite boring with the idea of replicating exactly this service, and I tried to spice it up a little bit, converting it into my personal version. As a stereotypical Italian, I chose to style is as Pizzagram, a social network of inviting pizza pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/pizzagram.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PIZZAGRAM&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, sometimes coding gets a little repetitive. Especially if you still are in a beginner stage, where every little details can cost pain and long struggles to be fixed. The drawback is that we have a pretty accurate model of how our code should look like, once we will be good at writing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a good piece of advice I can give to the newbies like me is: find ways to make the example projects more personal. Experiment. Mess up a little bit. It will put you in the unknown and outside your comfort zone, which is where you wanna be, to learn faster and better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always wondered where does all this modern, good looking CSS that we see nowadays in web applications come from. Apparently the majority of it comes from &lt;a href=&quot;http://getbootstrap.com/&quot;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;. If you look for a good and easy way to integrate fancy design into your application, give it a chance. It rocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need a pizza now. Later!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 47.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/08/day-47/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/08/day-47</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;HyperHipsterInstagramUser&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;ActiveRecord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Base&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;has_attached_file&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:cool_beard_image&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;validates_attachment_content_type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:cool_beard_image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:content_type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/\Aimage\/.*\Z/&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to England, having skipped the Monday lecture. I had my x-ray scan, and apparently I am healing. Had a physiotherapy session, as well, and it turned out to be quite painful. But I&amp;#39;m determined to be back at full service, so I&amp;#39;ll try and make the best out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the Makers colleagues at work, building a web version of the popular social media Instagram (which is the one I like and use the most). This seems a good start of the week, given that I already &lt;a href=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/26/day-38/&quot;&gt;had a glipse of it&lt;/a&gt; a couple of weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new feature we are learning to build, like my pseudo-code shows, is adding images to a new post, using a Ruby gem called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/thoughtbot/paperclip&quot;&gt;paperclip&lt;/a&gt;. A great walkthrough on how to go ahead with the whole process has been written by my classmate Johann. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nadavmatalon/great_book_of_walkthroughts/blob/master/walkthroughs/paperclip_Johann.md&quot;&gt;Find it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like working using walkthroughs, which are basically text files which describe the procedure to solve a common problem in an analytical way. They keep you focused, they do not help you too much, leaving a little bit of the concept to be figured out by the reader, and they can be modified and improved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a lighter note, here&amp;#39;s me with the cake that I got for my birthday in Italy. Pretty self-explanatory, huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/nerd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NERD&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out like a nerd.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Birthday Weekend.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/06/weekend/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/06/weekend</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Tlou_2lMLAc&quot;&gt;Home, sweet home.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/home.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HOME&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arm healing, good birthday, no vehicles randomly hitting me. Life was good to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 44.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/04/day-44/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/04/day-44</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;https://rubygems.org&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;retrospective&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:development&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday, here you come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that happens here every two weeks is the infamous Retrospective. It happens like this: usually at 4pm we stop doing what we are doing and we concentrate on talking together about ways to improve the overall experience, giving feedback and sharing our view with fellow Makers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I can&amp;#39;t say that I love it. I wouldn&amp;#39;t say that I hate it, but it goes on for a long couple of hours, and I have to stop what I am doing (that, being Friday, is often a challenge) and participate. This is usually my mindset when the retrospective begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But today I feel it went better than the other times. There was a part in which a couch was put at the center of the room, and we were supposed to talk if and only if we were sitting there. Usually I&amp;#39;m not the bigger fan of talking in public unless I have something really meaningful to say, and since a lot of juniors were expressing their frustration and fear of not moving forward, I took a breath and sat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told to them about my experience, with the broken arm and the inability to write and type properly. If that did not stop me from going forward and doing my best to get the most out of it, nothing should stop them. Makers is supposed to be the beginning of a long line, not a closed circle. I hope my message was received well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/retrospective.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RETROSPECTIVE&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off to Italy, to spend my birthday and have my arm checked, to see if it healed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fingers crossed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 43.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/03/day-43/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/03/day-43</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thursday has always been one of my least favorite days of the week. I can&amp;#39;t really say why. Bad memories are often always associated with Thursdays, in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week has been quite tough, and at this time of the day I feel more inclined not to blog about coding today. Tired does not describe what I am. This is a shame, since we are doing great things at Makers. But I&amp;#39;ll talk about that another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight I found a beautiful Thursday-related poem, by &lt;a href=&quot;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edna_St._Vincent_Millay&quot;&gt;Edna St. Vincent Millay&lt;/a&gt;, which is the one I put in my pseudo-code trademark style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;And if I loved you Wednesday,&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Well, what is that to you?&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;I do not love you Thursday&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;So much is true.&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;And why you come complaining&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Is more than I can see.&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;I loved you Wednesday, yes, but what&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Is that to me?&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 42.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/02/day-42/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/02/day-42</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;describe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;writing code&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;should be good dry code&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;write_application&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Meh.&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;have_content&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Meh. (★★★☆☆)&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey in the Yelp-like application is continuing.
Today we worked on &lt;a href=&quot;http://edgeguides.rubyonrails.org/active_record_validations.html&quot;&gt;data validations&lt;/a&gt; via Active Record, which is the Rails layer responsible for the model and data handling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am quite exausted so I don&amp;#39;t feel like writing a long post. But I&amp;#39;m quite happy with what we have done so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are able to handle data insertion, validation and handle events on the web page via &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ajax_%28programming%29&quot;&gt;AJAX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;#39;ll try a better overview of the application when I&amp;#39;ll see it finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And shout outs to KA, whose &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d1hDpufNXd0&quot;&gt;Night&amp;#39;s Gambit&lt;/a&gt; is helping me to be up till late working.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 41.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/07/01/day-41/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/07/01/day-41</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;Federicos-MacBook-Air:yelp federicomaffei&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;rspec

restaurants listing page
  no restaurants
    tells me there a no restaurants
  are restaurants
    should show the restaurant

restaurant creation form
  should be able to create a restaurant

restaurant edit form
  shound be able to edit a restaurant
  can delete restaurants

writing reviews
  should add the review of a resturant&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Rails, here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This framework works following the &lt;a href=&quot;http://betterexplained.com/articles/intermediate-rails-understanding-models-views-and-controllers/&quot;&gt;MVC paradigm&lt;/a&gt;. This means that we always design the behavior of the application using three entities: Models, Views, and Controllers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that every communication between the browser (the user side, your side, kind reader) and our application is handled by the Controller. The particular requests are handled and dispatched via Routes, that allow the controller to activate the Model, retrieve the data and ask the View to display it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Models are Ruby classes, that perform operations with the database, validate the data, execute low-level operations on it, and then return it to the controller to be routed to views. They do it using the class ActiveRecord::Base, that allows binding between the Ruby class and Database tables (in our case, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PostgreSQL&quot;&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt;). I&amp;#39;ll write more about Rails/DB interaction very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Views are the artists of the flat: they use HyperText Markup Language, Cascading Style Sheets, JavaScript, and a vast number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.princeton.edu/%7Eachaney/tmve/wiki100k/docs/Client-side_scripting.html&quot;&gt;client-side scripting languages&lt;/a&gt; to display nicely the required content or asset to the end-user. They don&amp;#39;t know what is happening behind the scenes: they just want go onstage and rock that crowd!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I am liking Rails, and I feel that this blog will be more and more tech-oriented as time passes and my confidence in what I know increases. I am a developer, after all, so why not share what I am learning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a lighter note, tonight I went to celebrate Canada Day at Birthdays, a nice Dalston bar. Unfortunately I did not manage to try their famous Poutine dish because they ran off of it (it was full of Canadians craving for it), but will definitely do as soon as I have the chance. I balanced with a couple of great IPA beers, so not bad at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/poutine.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;POUTINE&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll let you know if I like as soon as I get another chance to have that. Artist of the week? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cuHkUq1uSqE&quot;&gt;THE CHEF.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nite!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 40.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/06/30/day-40/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/30/day-40</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;rails new --help
rails new first_application -T -d postgresql
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;first_application
subl .
bundle
bin/rails generate rspec:install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday is never the best day of the week. Unless you work in a barber shop, which unfortunately is not true for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you spent the whole weekend moving your room from a flat to another with a broken arm, Monday is possibly the worst day ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not at Makers. Because today pieces are being put together. We are starting to learn &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyonrails.org/&quot;&gt;Rails.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that for those who know nothing about coding this is not much, but imagine that, if we were painters, today it would have been the first day we had a full color palette and a big empty canvas. This framework will allow us to build &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solution_stack&quot;&gt;full-stack web applications&lt;/a&gt; and put our ideas to realization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex introduced us to the topic, and this week we will build a Yelp-like website, with resturants listings, reviews and details, all with Rails. Here he is, doing his thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/alex.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ALEX&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Sam took over the afternoon, guiding us through the various steps of the environment setup and app building. I would lie if I told you that I understood everything, but tonight I&amp;#39;m going over the screencasts again and see what comes out. &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/SrYHoGMmR1s&quot;&gt;Staying positive&lt;/a&gt;, like I always tried to do in my London days, and as my man Mike Skinner taught me to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Night lads.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 38.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/06/26/day-38/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/26/day-38</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Cool Instagram App&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;form&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;search&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;method=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;post&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;input&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;type=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;text&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;tag&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;placeholder=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Enter a tag&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;button&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;type=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;submit&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;button&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Search for a tag:&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/form&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;target&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, seems that the JavaScript and jQuery galore has reached high peaks here at Makers.
We used the &lt;a href=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/25/day-37/&quot;&gt;GitHub API&lt;/a&gt; so much that they blocked us and left us without our test platform, since if they receive to many requests at once they are forced to block the IP address that sent them (us, in this case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least no one can say that we are not hard workers at Makers, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This led me and Julia to pair program together, with the aim to build an app that uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/developer/&quot;&gt;Instagram APIs&lt;/a&gt; instead of the blocked GitHub ones. We thought that it could have been fun to fiddle with APIs a little bit, both of us being Instagram enthusiasts. And we were right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/instagram.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;INSTAGRAM&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time we managed to reach some nice and pleasant results, like a little application that allows you to find and show photos by searching a tag. Here&amp;#39;s a little screenshot. Overall a productive and fun day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mGgMZpGYiy8&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/a&gt;, then!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 37.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/06/25/day-37/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/25/day-37</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ready&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;#add_profile&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;on&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;submit&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;preventDefault&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;username&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;#username&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;val&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;https://api.github.com/users/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;username&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;newProfile&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Mustache&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;render&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;#profile-template&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;.profile-container&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;newProfile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Javascript and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JQuery&quot;&gt;jQuery&lt;/a&gt; madness going on at Makers.
Today I actually posted here a chunk of code I have written, instead of the usual mocking one, since I am quite proud of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex showed us how to develop a dynamic content page which retrieves data from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and shows it as a result of a search. This means that now our static HTML is powered by the combination of Javascript and jQuery (which is basically a library that has access to the HTML document and extends Javascript, allowing to retrieve, process and add content from and to the page itself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case we have learned how to take an user&amp;#39;s input (a GitHub username) and via &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_programming_interface&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; obtain data about that user (username, avater, followers, repos) and put that into the page in a nice and animated way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course this new language is hard to  grasp. Of course programming in Ruby was like talking in Italian while JS looks a bit like English, in a way. But this is a time of challenges, so how bad can be another one? Plus this thing of being able to handle data from big applications and sites is fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On another side of my life - flatmates are moving back to Paris, and this means I have to look for a new flat this week. I&amp;#39;ll miss them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/flatmates.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FLATMATES&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Night.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 36.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/06/24/day-36/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/24/day-36</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Football&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;player1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;player2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;player1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Italia&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;player2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Uruguay&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Football&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;prototype&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;loser&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Italia&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning of the week and beginning of this second half of the Makers adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex took over the lectures, and begun to teach us &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JavaScript&quot;&gt;Javascript&lt;/a&gt; right away. It is another language, totally different from Ruby (it is a client-side language and the syntax differs to some extent). But in the end I liked switching from a language to another. It adds spice to the already tasty coding dish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are building a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rock-paper-scissors&quot;&gt;Rock-Paper-Scissors&lt;/a&gt; application, and it seems real fun to fiddle around with Javascript. Nice effects can be added to the static pages, and even if setting them up is not always straightforward, I am having a good time. Maybe it is also because my shoulder is getting relatively better, not that I can type, but at least I carry on through the day without painkillers, and I manage to remove the bandage every evening for at least a couple hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All going to be fine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except Italy, we are out the World Cup and we played like shit. Well deserved, Uruguay. Except for you, Suarez, you biting cheat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/suarez.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SUAREZ&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But anyway, what can I say. I love football, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nMO5Ko_77Hk&quot;&gt;love is a losing game&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least for me, it has always been like that, and maybe always will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Night.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 33.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/06/20/day-33/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/20/day-33</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cohort&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Cohort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:month&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;may&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cohort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;update&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:status&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;SENIORS&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduation day, today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means two things: our seniors are now officially Makers with all due honours, and that we, the mighty May clan, are Seniors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just can&amp;#39;t believe that half the experience is already gone. Man, this journey is so short!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The projects presented by the guys at the ceremony were impressive: a beautifully interfaced task organizer, a clever online buy/sell platform, and a funny application to handle money collecting from friends when organizing a social event. Well done, March cohort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can I say about this first half, as seen from my eyes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I learned a lot, about myself more than about coding, in a way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have great motivation, but not always the skill of channeling it in something positive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I broke my shoulder but still somehow managed to get along and keep working hard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am a shy person, in a way. Capable of bonding with the cohort mates but less able to do so with the coaches and staff, maybe for a lack of faith in my spoken english? I always feel I don&amp;#39;t understand everything completely, and I often retract from making questions and interacting. I want to do more, and I have the time to do so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a lighter note, watched the Italia game with Costa Rica while the graduation party was going. Worst idea ever. What a shitty team today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/lost.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;LOST&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FAnGnevKxJE&quot;&gt;May cohort, let&amp;#39;s take over.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 32.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/06/19/day-32/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/19/day-32</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;federicomaffei&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# \c bookmark_manager_development &lt;/span&gt;
You are now connected to database &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;bookmark_manager_development&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; as user &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;federicomaffei&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;.
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;bookmark_manager_development&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# select * from users;&lt;/span&gt;
 id &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;           email           &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;                       password_digest                        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; password_token &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; password_token_time 
----+---------------------------+--------------------------------------------------------------+----------------+---------------------
  &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; federico.maffei@gmail.com &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$2a$10$pywCClfPGCgsAjnjsxkV&lt;/span&gt;.uhHWPal1VIJn5soHIhR1nHp1Zm5rc9uO &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; row&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Databases, Data Mappers, Data models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We seem to be introducing data handling and security in our coding skills, aren&amp;#39;t we?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today the March cohort rehearsed the presentation of their final projects, which they&amp;#39;ll show tomorrow at the graduation day. The applications they built seem really cool and based on good ideas. I&amp;#39;ll be happy to attend the ceremony and check them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, starting tomorrow we&amp;#39;ll be seniors, the eldest in Makers Academy and the grown ups, so to speak. I like the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed until late today at Makers, watching the game with some of the guys. Here&amp;#39;s how my coding setup was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/footy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SETUP&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exhausted, off to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ycu7i7hbcFU&quot;&gt;Outta here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 31.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/06/18/day-31/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/18/day-31</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;-----&amp;gt; Ruby app detected
-----&amp;gt; Compiling Ruby/Rack
-----&amp;gt; Using Ruby version: ruby-2.0.0
-----&amp;gt; Installing dependencies using 1.6.3
       Running: bundle install --without development:test --path vendor/bundle --binstubs vendor/bundle/bin -j4 --deployment
       Using addressable 2.3.6
       Using mini_portile 0.6.0
       Using rack 1.5.2
       Using fastercsv 1.5.5
       Using json 1.8.1
       Using json_pure 1.8.1
       Using multi_json 1.10.1
       Using stringex 1.5.1
       Using bcrypt 3.1.7
       Using mime-types 2.3
       Using uuidtools 2.1.4
       Using database_cleaner 1.3.0
       Using tilt 1.4.1
       Using bundler 1.6.3
       Using dm-core 1.2.1
       Using data_objects 0.10.14
       Using launchy 2.4.2
       Using nokogiri 1.6.2.1
       Using rack-test 0.6.2
       Using rack-flash3 1.0.5
       Using rack-protection 1.5.3
       Using bcrypt-ruby 3.1.5
       Using dm-constraints 1.2.0
       Using dm-aggregates 1.2.0
       Using dm-migrations 1.2.0
       Using dm-serializer 1.2.2
       Using dm-timestamps 1.2.0
       Using dm-transactions 1.2.0
       Using dm-validations 1.2.0
       Using do_postgres 0.10.14
       Using dm-do-adapter 1.2.0
       Using xpath 2.0.0
       Using sinatra 1.4.5
       Using dm-types 1.2.2
       Using capybara 2.3.0
       Using dm-postgres-adapter 1.2.0
       Using data_mapper 1.2.0
       Your bundle is &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;complete&lt;/span&gt;!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intense week, as the Makers cliché wants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not updating the blog as much as I want, but it is not too easy with only one hand at my disposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are approaching the sixth week, and in a while we will enter the second half of the course and become seniors. Time fled, as always when you do something that you enjoy a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now the project we are working on is allowing us to put some pieces together: modeling data with the help of DataMapper, an &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-relational_impedance_mismatch&quot;&gt;Object Relational Mapper&lt;/a&gt;, writing the main application in Ruby, and the user interface in ERB, which is basically still Ruby, but embedded in HTML. I feel like I&amp;#39;m ready to write more descriptive posts about coding, and I&amp;#39;ll start doing so as soon as I remove the bendage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still feel somehow confused by the amount of new information being thrown at me each day, but slowly getting used to it. And coding has a big upside: you can do it while listening to music, and this is giving me the chance to go through all of my favorite albums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/doomsday.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DOOM&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hL5cun2kQ6M&amp;amp;feature=kp&quot;&gt;MF DOOM&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; week. God how much I love this rap shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YO.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Weekend II.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/06/14/weekend/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/14/weekend</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Weekend was all right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/balo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mario&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:-)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 24 - London lights.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/06/12/day-24/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/12/day-24</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;Federicos-MacBook-Air:battleships federicomaffei&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git add .
Federicos-MacBook-Air:battleships federicomaffei&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git commit -m &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;battleship can hit a ship!&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;master f2267cf&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; battleships can hit a ship!
 &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; files changed, &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;46&lt;/span&gt; insertions&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;+&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
Federicos-MacBook-Air:battleships federicomaffei&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week is busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to move on with a slow but constant pace, not being able to write properly but still optimistic. We are quite confused, as a class, since the Ruby part of the course has been increasingly difficult and full of hurdles, and the morale of the troops is not the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mine as well, considering my arm, but I&amp;#39;m proud of myself, since I decided to write the Battleship thing again by myself, with decent results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today has been a fairly productive day, all in all. We are starting to address the front-end part of software development, that is the part that is closer to the user, and involves other languages. Leaving Ruby for a bit will be good. I don&amp;#39;t want to be too focused on one thing, risking tunnel vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather here in London is being pretty amazing, and I want to share a picture I took when out of class tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/london.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;London&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazing, isn&amp;#39;t it?
Plus the World Cup is about to start, and on Saturday it&amp;#39;s going to be Italy vs. England. Can&amp;#39;t wait!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VcDEOYWu80E&quot;&gt;This for good wishing.&lt;/a&gt; Out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 22 - Battleshits.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/06/10/day-22/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/10/day-22</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;battleships&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;NAH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not blogging every day now, and I regret it a little bit. I don&amp;#39;t feel like doing so, and I prefer to save the only working hand I have left for coding as much as I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The days at Makers are long, we are still stuck on the battleships project that the class started when I was home, and no one seems to enjoy it that much. I am trying really hard to be level with the class, hoping to be better soon and kick ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday Will gave me a little plastic scooter that I enjoyed very much. Overall I tried to have the best start of the week possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/scooter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Scooter&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I am now, exhausted at home, typing with my left hand and trying to keep optimistic. Can&amp;#39;t go much worse than now, anyway!
The last six months have been a rollercoaster of events and feelings. I made some big decisions. I felt awful at times, angry with the world and with people. This is my escape, I felt so better after making up my mind, and I&amp;#39;ll go all the way, no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/SrYHoGMmR1s&quot;&gt;Song of the evening.&lt;/a&gt; And I&amp;#39;m out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 17 - Back.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/06/05/day-17/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/05/day-17</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;plane&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;describe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;comeback&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;happened today and I want to give everything to be back on track&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;comeback&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;comeback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;be_thursday&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erick Sermon and Parish Smith know &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=noegD-jIw5Y&quot;&gt;their shit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I bumped hard their album Back in Business. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/beatles.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beatles&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federico is like a Beatle, back with another single! Yes, I&amp;#39;m back in London, back at Makers, and back for good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been in a hospital in Italy, on a plane to UK and at school until 19 pm all the same day. So excuse me while I kiss my pillow. Nite!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Days 14 and 15 - HELL.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/06/02/day-14-15/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/02/day-14-15</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;No usual nerd code sample today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No music links, no jokes, no nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last two days have been just bad. And they could have been worse, but my cohort mates and coaches really tried to make me feel part of the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended the lectures via Hangout, and Enrique made sure I had a proper audio and got every bit of the talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/enrique.png&quot; alt=&quot;LECTURE&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked via remote with Johann, Kate, Will and Jamie. The weekly project is a Battleship game, but I can&amp;#39;t help feeling a little bit lost and behind. Especially today I was really knocked out by painkillers and lack of sleep, and did not manage to help much during the designing and testing of the first classes. The guys were really supportive and patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My arm is senseless, and hurts like hell. I broke an ankle before, but this is really agony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, I do not know if I even stand the chance of finishing the cohort like this. I can&amp;#39;t even type properly. I did not speak with Enrique or anyone of the coaches about this, and I don&amp;#39;t think I&amp;#39;ll receive any particular feedback if I do. It&amp;#39;s all up to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left my job, my country and my records to be here and become a developer. And now here I am, 4 weeks into the course and with one working arm less. Scared about the future, to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish me good, kind reader.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Weekend Days.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/06/01/weekend/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/06/01/weekend</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bones&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;each&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bone&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;  
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bone&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;broken?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;    
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;break&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;accident&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;happens?&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/broken.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BED&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plans are great, unless they fail and leave you diving deep into a shit pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How it was supposed to be: go to Italy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xlrqaAjBwS4&quot;&gt;attend wedding and party with old time friends like there&amp;#39;s no tomorrow&lt;/a&gt;, take a plane on Monday morning and be at Makers by lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How it actually went: a scooter ran over me on Saturday night, my right shoulder broke in two points, spent the night at the hospital, still went to the wedding and tried to drink away the pain, woke up today in the worst pain I ever experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, stuck here in Italy for the next two days, I&amp;#39;m awaiting for a x-ray check, unable to write or do anything else with my arm, and not sleeping from pain. But still trying to be optimistic and not give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not give up.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 13 - course % 3 == 0</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/05/30/day-13/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/05/30/day-13</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;WeekFullError&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;StandardError&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;initialize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;msg&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Week&amp;#39;s over.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;super&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s8mht4FuVrU&quot;&gt;Friday, venerdì&lt;/a&gt;, again.
After a quick calculation, that can be done without any coding, one third of the course already flew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;33,3333333333%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was challenge day, and I must say I find myself really at ease while trying to complete the test, way more than following the code proposed in the weekly project. It was something related to traffic control applied to the case of an airport. Nothing too difficult, it took me three hours to go through it and it was interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But anyway, enough with the coding adventures. Tomorrow at 6am I have to catch a plane to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancona&quot;&gt;my hometown&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;#39;ll be there for a couple of days to attend the wedding of one of my best friends.
I can&amp;#39;t wait to be there, it&amp;#39;s been quite long since last time I&amp;#39;ve been back. I&amp;#39;ll post a couple pictures of the wedding on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, and my beard is starting to look like a real coder&amp;#39;s one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/beard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BEARD&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off to bed, yo.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 12 - I love bicycles</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/05/29/day-12/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/05/29/day-12</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Bike&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;DAMMIT I NEED A BIKE IN MY LIFE, A REAL ONE.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usual big working day here, pairing with Julia and getting on with good results on the Boris Bikes project, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tfl.gov.uk/modes/cycling/barclays-cycle-hire&quot;&gt;(here&amp;#39;s the real one)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But today I feel like writing more about me and my inner feelings, since this project is hitting on a nerve. Emo shit will follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fucking miss my bike. I actually loved her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/bike.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MY ONLY LOVE&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left her (yes, she&amp;#39;s a lady) in Milan, and I still haven&amp;#39;t copped one here in London, for a number of reasons. I miss riding her (no double entendre here) and cruising the city streets and alleys.
So I decided that next week I&amp;#39;ll empty my pockets and buy another one, and yes, I know it sounds like betrayal, but I really need to surf this concrete jungle with some wheels.
Since my flat is relatively small and has no courtyard, I guess I&amp;#39;ll settle for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Folding_bicycle&quot;&gt;folding one&lt;/a&gt;, even if it sounds weird to have a bike that folds itself. We&amp;#39;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On to the friday, anyway! Cheers lads.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 11 - Big Wednesday</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/05/28/day-11/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/05/28/day-11</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;ThisWednesday&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;include&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Week&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;learn_encapsulation&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giant leaps forward this week at Makers.
Today we started talking seriously about the concepts of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Encapsulation_%28object-oriented_programming%29&quot;&gt;encapsulation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inheritance_%28object-oriented_programming%29&quot;&gt;class inheritance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically it takes what we&amp;#39;ve learned so far about classes to another level, allowing us to take advantage of similarities between classes, and extending them using the methods we already declared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day was productive, I paired with Johann and we completed a good part of the week project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off-topic: I am so glad it is Wednesday and I can go relieve my stress in a football pitch. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5hFH3q5bz1Q&quot;&gt;Big Wednesday!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/bigw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BIG WEDNESDAY&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 10 - A real player needs Class.</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/05/27/day-10/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/05/27/day-10</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Player&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;initialize&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@knows_about_classes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;after_this_tuesday&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@knows_about_classes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we&amp;#39;re back, after a long long weekend. The week started with a big juicy lecture about Ruby &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Class_%28computer_programming%29&quot;&gt;classes&lt;/a&gt;.
Now some pieces of the puzzle are starting to combine in a nice way altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel really tired and not too keen on blogging about the whole day, that has been basically devoted to understand the basics of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-oriented_design&quot;&gt;OOD&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-oriented_programming&quot;&gt;OOP&lt;/a&gt; with a bit of CRC cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does all of it mean? We&amp;#39;ll see, maybe I&amp;#39;ll explain in a longer post soon. For now what I got is that objects and classes are like people and behave like people, and I don&amp;#39;t know if a plus or a minus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But overall good day, with a lot of new stuff to learn. Really looking forward to be in class again tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, speaking of class, how did you expect an Italian would end this post?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/baggio.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BAGGIO&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long live Roberto.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 9 - TGIF</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/05/23/day-9/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/05/23/day-9</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;week_end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;day&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;wednesday&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Two days left&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;thursday&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;One day left&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;friday&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;WEEKEND, LADS.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today has been a day of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nJGEOB5nTrw&quot;&gt;highs and lows&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started quite low and went progressively better until the afternoon.
It is Friday, end of the second week, and I&amp;#39;m just tired as you could imagine.
I completed the code challenge with no particular struggling (it was quite easy), then I went on programming a little bit by myself, until we were all (us and the March cohort) caught in a Retrospective, that is a way for the coaches to receive feedback and comments from us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt quite relieved in seeing I am not the only one feeling lost sometimes, and that it is normal not to finish a weekly project in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am strongly motivated to get my next week to be better than this one, and reach the goal of asking more focused questions during the lectures. We&amp;#39;ll see. In the meanwhile, I&amp;#39;m off to a few drinks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOOD WEEKEND LADS!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/tgif.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;TGIF&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.mamatoga.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/tgif_14.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;tgif&quot;&gt; --&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 8 - AKA Day Hate</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/05/22/day-8/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/05/22/day-8</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;understanding of mocks&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;describe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;trying to catch stdin - stdout&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;did not happen&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;STDIN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:gets&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;and_return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;FALSE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no love without hate, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcmGMggfgec&quot;&gt;if the Wu Tang says so&lt;/a&gt;, I believe them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently this is my feeling towards Ruby: I really enjoy learning it, but today it gave me hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can I say: my day at Makers started just fine - but during the day it definitely turned out to be difficult, to say the least. I worked hard on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.relishapp.com/rspec&quot;&gt;rspec&lt;/a&gt; Student Directory project, and banged my head on several development problems, that I did not manage to tackle at all. Nic and Jamie helped me and gave me a couple of good hints, but I&amp;#39;m still stuck on grasping some small but apparently important concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to handle user input tests by implementing mocking, but it turned out that it was not that fun. Plus I stumbled upon several articles that incresed my skepticalness on it being useful. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, at 7pm I called it a day, and here I am now, blogging and having a good roasted chicken to finish cooking in the oven. 
Here it is, in all its glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/pollo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;POLLO&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 7 - rspecrspecrspec</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/05/21/day-7/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/05/21/day-7</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;half an hour of time to blog&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;describe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;trying to find time&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;while testing methods&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;find_ten_minutes_today&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;be_false&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time, time, time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RMxRDTfzgpU&quot;&gt;Like Satchmo sang&lt;/a&gt;, we have all the time in the world.
But apparently here at Makers it is not always true, especially when learning &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test-driven_development&quot;&gt;Test Driven Development&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last two days have been really challenging. It turned out that the project we were working on was not coded properly, and that without testing, no line of code shall pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pair-programmed with Will these last two days, and we worked pretty hard to get things going. I&amp;#39;m happy with the results achieved, and I see everyone of us really focused. We&amp;#39;ll see if tomorrow we&amp;#39;ll be able to finish this endless list of names, cohorts, emails, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I left at 19,30 - at this was my face just before leaving. You be the judge. Later yo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://federicomaffei.github.io/public/images/f_makers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ME&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>week.first(), post.first()</title>
   <link href="http://federicomaffei.github.io//2014/05/20/first-post/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://federicomaffei.github.io/2014/05/20/first-post</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;learn coding at makers&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;describe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;overloading my brain&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;while completing my first week&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;my_brain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;be_empty&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All right, here I am. Blogging for the first time in my life, about something that I&amp;#39;m doing for the first time in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding. Learning how to develop software with my own brain and hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been telling myself to open up this blog since day one here at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makersacademy.com&quot;&gt;Makers&lt;/a&gt;, but really did not even have the time to actually do it, until now. And of course promised myself to keep on updating it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first week has been a real rollercoaster. I got to meet my cohort mates, which I&amp;#39;m sure I&amp;#39;ll get to know better over the next weeks, and I dived into the code. I paired with Sasha, and overall the working session has been constructive and promising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically we got our hands dirty on a project that involves a directory of students, and has the purpose of getting us in the right frame of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enrique, our teacher for this first week, then gave us a coding &lt;a href=&quot;http://codekata.com/&quot;&gt;Kata&lt;/a&gt; (that&amp;#39;s what they call them) to complete over the weekend.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/95677099&quot;&gt;This is the result, ready for you to watch on Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;. Check it!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
